

MANISHKRISHNA RAMAKRISHNAN

- CHENNAI, INDIA 600078
- +91 8122790831
- manizkrish96@gmail.com

SUMMARY

An Enthusiastic and Committed person with 5+ years of experience in IT infrastructure and as an AWS DevOps professional. Over 3+ years of hand-on experience in AWS DevOps tools and cloud services. Strong work ethic and dedicated to quality assurance. Works great with team members under Agile and Scrum frameworks.

SKILLS

Amazon Web Services: Ec2, S3, RDS, Vpc, IAM, Elb, Asg, Route53, SNS, SQS, CloudWatch, CloudFront and Lambda. Infrastructure as Code (IaC): Terraform Microservice and Containerization:

Docker and Kubernetes.

CI/CD Pipeline : Jenkins and AWS

CodePipeline.

Monitoring and Logging: Prometheus,

Grafana and Splunk.

Configuration Management: Ansible.

EXPERIENCE

DEVOPS ENGINEER, 04/2020 - Current

Mindtree, CHENNAI, INDIA

LIFE INSURANCE CLIENT - MIRAE ASSET

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Having experience in Cloud Infrastructure using Amazon Web Services (AWS).
 Leveraging various services such as EC2, S3, EFS, IAM, Load Balancer, Auto
 Scaling, VPC, Route 53, CloudFront, CloudWatch, and RDS. I have used EBS and EFS as per requirements to ensure efficient storage solutions.
- Worked on creating IAM user groups, and defining roles policies.
- Creating/Managing backup and recovery through AMI's for critical Ec2 instances and Snapshots.

- Collaborated with development, QA and IT operations staff to enhance software productivity.
- Significant experience on Git as a Version Control System focusing on code management through GitHub repositories
- Furthermore, I have hands-on experience on robust CI/CD pipelines using Jenkins. Worked with DOCKER and KUBERNETES for deployment instrumental in transitioning from a monolithic architecture to a microservices architecture.
- I have demonstrated in utilizing Sona type Nexus repositories for efficient management of artifacts and dependencies.
- I possess strong skill in creating and managing the infrastructure using TERRAFORM and ANSIBLE.

HEALTHCARE CLIENT - SeaSpine

ROLES AND RESPONSIBILITIES

- Worked extensively on AWS services like Ec2, Elb, Auto Scaling, EBS, S3, Vpc, IAM, Cloudwatch.
- Managed and created users and group accounts with required roles and policy restrictions using IAM service.
- Installed and setup Web servers like Apache and Tomcat.
- Integrated and configured CI/CD through jenkins plug-in, created master-slave configuration for parallel builds.
- Worked on Docker containers for different environments.
- Well-versed in Linux administration duties, including installation and maintenance tasks. Overall, I bring extensive experience and knowledge in AWS cloud and DevOps tools.

DESKTOP SUPPORT, 05/2018 - 04/2020

Mindtree

- Respond to user tickets related to hardware, software, and networking problems
- Guide users through the installation process of applications and computer peripherals
- Perform remote troubleshooting to address issues without physical access to the computer
- Explore different solutions and pathways until a resolution is found
- Customize desktop applications to align with the specific needs of users
- Maintain a log of technical issues and their corresponding solutions for future reference.

CNC OPERATOR, 05/2017 - 06/2018

GOBAL TECHNOLOGY

- Well versed in programming, setting-up and operating a CNC Machine
- Set-up and manage CNC machines to perform different jobs including drilling and grinding
- Translate engineering drawings and requirements into dimensions for production.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Prathyusha Engineering College, Chennai, TamilNadu, 01/2017 **U.G**: **MECHCANICAL**

LANGUAGES

- TAMIL
- ENGLISH